# SHIV SHANKAR PRASAD

Full Stack Web Developer

### **DETAILS**

#### **ADDRESS**

Muzaffarpur India

#### **PHONE**

8969308829

#### **EMAIL**

shivshankarkumar.pusa@gmail.com

### LINKS

**Itsindianguy Blog** 

Gitlab Profile

Stack Overflow Profile

Github Profile

Linked In

### **SKILLS**

React

JavaScript

Next Js

NODE.JS

### **PROFILE**

MERN Stack Web developer.

Experienced and Passionate for MERN Stack Web developer to adapt in all stages of advanced web development. Writing clean code and equipped with a diverse and promising skill-set having good knowledge of React js, Its framework Next JS. Material UI, Redux, hooks . Made Myself a website and deployed on Firebase. Very good team player, and very fast learner.

### **EMPLOYMENT HISTORY**

# Full Stack Developer, Zapbuild Technologies PVT LTD.

Mohali

Jan 2020 — Feb 2021

My work there was to make the all logical part of the website including the backend and the frontend part. Backend was on Laravel ( PHP framework ) and Frontend was on the React js( Library of Javascript ).

There i worked on two different live projects, one was for the cannabis product and stores with different stores and second was for Listings and selling the properties.

### System Engineer | MERN Stack Developer,-Tata Consultancy Services

Noida

Feb 2021 — Present

I am working as a Full Stack developer in a project. My role is to create and manage API integrations, Frontend designs using React js, React hooks, react MUI, Redux for state handling, jsx, babel and more.

Working on node js as the backend, using its Express js web application framework, its components, NPM, Events, buffers, FileSystem, making the backend more fast and stable and scalable.

Express.js
PHP
Git
MongoDB
Laravel Framework
HTML & CSS

### **HOBBIES**

Coding, Learning new technologies, Cooking, Adobe Photoshop, Reading Novels.

### LANGUAGES

Hindi

English

### **EDUCATION**

# B. Tech, Maharishi Dayanand University, Rohtak (Haryana )

Bhiwāni

Jul 2016 — Jun 2020

Graduated with high honors in Computer Science and Engineering with distinction.

### **INTERNSHIPS**

## Full Stack Developer, Neoverse Private Limited

Bhiwani

Jun 2019 — Jul 2019

Created and implemented an online compiler which was used to run program for different languages.

User technologies were PHP (core PHP ), Javascript (Core javascript for the frontend and frontend validations).

### Java stack developer, NIKS Techonologies

Patna

May 2018 — Jun 2020

Worked on making a School Management system and had to implement the both front end and the backend of the Project. I implemented dynamic Panels custom desktop designs and implementing the logical part of the project.